A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 1-3254 FA739A
Rockefeller Archive Center
- A special style for a special clientele: assessment of a grant to the University of Montreal, Canada, for research and training in criminology (Reports 002797), 1972; Cochran, Robert; Goldmann, Robert, 1921- (Box 123)
  "Assessment of a grant to the University of Montreal, Canada, for research and training in criminology." --T.p.
  07100191
  The University of Montreal
  Partial general support of the International Center for Comparative Criminology.
  Crimonology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Finance; Criminal justice, Administration of -- Study and teaching (Higher); Criminologists -- Training of; Endowments -- Canada -- Evaluation; International Centre for Comparative Criminology
- A symposium on the use of non-human primates for research on problems of human reproduction (Reports 002798), 1971; Mahoney, Richard T.; Standley, C. C. (Box 123)
  Primates -- Research; Human reproduction -- Research; Fertilization (Biology) -- Research; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Agriculture development in tropical Africa and the role of the Ford Foundation (Reports 002799), 1970; Hanson, Haldore (Box 123)
  Paper originally presented at Trustee's meeting, December 11-12, 1970.
  L72-236.
  24 p. + attachments: map, tables
  Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Congresses; Food supply -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Congresses; Green Revolution -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Congresses
- Report of the internal Foundation conference on Ford Foundation programs in Europe: February 24-25, 1971 (Reports 002800) (Box 123)
  Charity organization -- Europe
- Log notes on visit to the University of Pittsburgh (Reports 002801), 1967; Gwatkin, Davidson R. (Box 123)
  Population -- Economic aspects -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Population research -- Developing countries; Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Curricula; Scholarships -- United States; Population; Ford Foundation. Population Program; University of Pittsburgh
- Rehabilitation potential of western coal lands: A report to the Energy Policy Project of the Ford Foundation (Reports 002802-001), 1974
  National Academy of Sciences (U.S.)
- Reproductive health: A strategy for the 1990's (Reports 002802-002), 1991
- Seizing opportunities: the role of CDCs in urban economic development (Reports 002802-003), undated
- Selected studies on energy: Background papers for energy: The next twenty years (Reports 002802-004), 1980; Landsberg, Hans H.
- Seminars on media and society 1974-1980: A summary and casebook (Reports 002802-005)
- Solving the math problem: the Ford Foundation's work on reforming middle and secondary school mathematics, 1980-1998 (Reports 002802-006), undated
- They Went to College Early: Evaluation Report Number 2 (Reports 002802-007), 1957
  Fund for the Advancement of Education (U.S.)
- Too Little, Too Late: Services for Teenage Parents: A Working Paper from the Ford Foundation (Reports 002802-008), 1982; McGee, Elizabeth A.
- The Ford Foundation Management and Program Trends in the Fifties and Sixties (Reports 002802-009), 1971 (Box 123)
  Provides statistical information about Foundation management patterns and grant-making activities during the 1950's and 60's.
  Office of Communications;Office of the Secretary
  [Ford Foundation publications]
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Charity organization -- United States; Philanthropy
- National Center of Agriculture, Chapingo, Mexico (Reports 002803-001), 1963 (Box 123)
  One of four discussion papers presented at the Trustees meeting, June 20-21, 1963.
  Agricultural extension work -- Research -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Research -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Mexico; Agriculture and state -- Mexico; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Conference (1963 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Organization (Reports 002803-002), 1963 (Box 123)
  City planning -- India -- Calcutta (India); Urbanization -- India -- Calcutta (India); Community development -- India; West Bengal. Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Organisation; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Conference (1963 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- College of Agriculture, Los Banos, Philippines (Reports 002803-003), 1963 (Box 123)
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Philippines; Universities and colleges -- Philippines; Education, Higher -- Philippines -- Evaluation; Higher education and state -- Philippines; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Conference (1963 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.); University of the Philippines. College of Agriculture
- Programs in education, public affairs, and humanities and the arts for North Carolina (Reports 002803-004), 1963 (Box 123)
  Overseas Division;Education
  Education -- North Carolina; Educational assistance -- United States; Manpower policy -- North Carolina; Manpower policy -- United States; Humanities -- Study and teaching -- North Carolina; Humanities -- Study and teaching; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Conference (1963 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- Citizen education in world affairs (Reports 002804), 1964 (Box 123)
  International relations -- Study and teaching -- United States; International relations -- Citizen participation; Education and globalization; Foreign Policy Association
- Your child up to five years of age - a guidebook for Arab women (Reports 002805), 1974; Othman, Saniyah. (Box 123)
  Child care -- Arab countries -- Guidebooks; Child development -- Arab countries -- Guidebooks; Child rearing -- Arab countries -- Guidebooks
- Proposed financial support program for educational television stations (Reports 002806), 1965 (Box 123)
  Television in education -- United States; Educational television stations -- United States -- Finance; Public broadcasting -- United States -- Finance
- Land acquisition (Reports 002807), 1964 (Box 123)
  Discusses the implications of funding projects which use the acquisition of land as a technique to conserve natural resources.
  Conservation projects (Natural resources) -- United States; Ecology -- United States
- Leadership Fellows Program, 1966-68 (Reports 002808), 1968 (Box 123)
  Prepared for the Education Committee of the Board of Trustees. --T.p
  Education -- United States; Educational leadership -- United States; Scholarships -- United States; Teachers -- Training of -- United States
- Overseas Development Program: South and Southeast Asia, Lower Mekong Basin (Reports 002809), 1963 (Box 123)
  Watershed management -- Economic aspects -- Mekong River Watershed; Water resources development -- Mekong River Watershed; Water resources development -- Southeast Asia; Water-power -- Research -- Mekong River Watershed; Water-power -- Research -- Southeast Asia; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia
- The International Rice Research Institute: its record to date, and recommendations for continuing support (Reports 002810), 1969 (Box 123)
  Research institutes -- Philippines; Agriculture -- Research; Agricultural development projects -- Asia; International Rice Research Institute
- International politics and the Foundation's international programs (Reports 002811), 1965 (Box 123)
  Politics and culture -- Developing countries -- Communist countries; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- Overseas Development Program: International Institute of Tropical Agriculture located in Nigeria (Reports 002812), 1966 (Box 123)
  Restrictions removed, December 2014.
  Agriculture -- Research -- Nigeria; Agriculture and state -- Nigeria
- Innovations in university finance (Reports 002813), 1967 (Box 123)
  Universities and colleges -- United States -- Finance; Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance; Yale University
- Ford Foundation mission to Argentina, August-September, 1959 (Reports 002814), 1960; Wolf, Alfred C.; Silvert, Kalman H.; Carlson, Reynold E. (Reynold Erland) (Box 123)
  11, 16 p. + attachment
  Charity organization -- Argentina; Charity organization -- Latin America; Economic assistance -- Argentina; Philanthropy -- Argentina
- Higher education in the Argentine Republic (Reports 002815), 1959; Márquez, Angel Diego (Box 123)
  Education, Higher -- Argentina -- History; Education, Higher -- Research -- Argentina; Higher education and state -- Argentina; Universities and colleges -- Argentina -- History
- The Ford Foundation and Foundation-supported activities in India 1951-1956 (Reports 002816), 1957 (Box 123)
  "The Ford Foundation's work in India began in the early autumn of 1951, when Paul Hoffman, then President and Director of the Ford Foundation, visited India at the invitation of Prime Minister Nehru, to discuss ways in which the Foundation could ... help
  Charity organization -- India; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- India
- The Ford Foundation and Foundation-supported activities in India (Reports 002817), 1960 (Box 123)
  20 p.: tables
  Charity organization -- India; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- India; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- The Ford Foundation and Foundation supported activities in India (Reports 002818), 1960 (Box 123)
- Overseas Development Program - Pakistan: plans and estimates January, 1956 to (Reports 002819), 1959 (Box 123)
  Charity organization -- Pakistan; Endowments -- Pakistan -- Evaluation
- International training and research programs - China Program (Reports 002820), 1955 (Box 123)
  Excerpt from agenda for meeting of Advisory Committee on International Training and Research.
  Charity organization -- China; Central planning -- China
- Population Program: Institute of Human Reproduction, December 1963/ Ford Foundation. (Reports 002821) (Box 123)
  A number of distinguished scientists and clinicians have proposed that this Foundation help to establish in the United States an institute of human reproduction for fundatmental and applied biological research aimed at achieving improved methods of fertilization. Confidential.,Includes later [January 1964] paper with same title.
  Overseas Division/Population Program
  Human reproduction -- Research; Birth control -- Research; Fertility, Human -- Research; Research institutes -- Finance; International cooperation; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Anatomy of the corporate liquidity crisis (Reports 002822), 1970 (Box 123)
  Finance/Office of the Treasurer
  162 p. + appendices: tables
  Liquidity (Economics) -- Research; Investments -- United States -- Research; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance
- Organizing for agricultural development (Reports 002823), 1963; Hill, F. F. (Forrest Frank); Mosher, Arthur Theodore (Box 123)
  Overseas Division/Administration
  Agricultural assistance -- Developing countries; Agricultural productivity -- Developing countries; Agricultural development projects -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- The development of Southeast Asian studies in Southeast Asia (Reports 002824), 1968; Sharp, Lauriston (Box 123)
  21 p. + appendices
  Education, Higher -- United States; Education, Higher -- Southeast Asia
- A comprehensive information service in administration and implementation of family planning programs (Reports 002825), 1966; Jaffe, Frederick S.; Shelley, Edwin F. (Box 123)
  "The information and recommendations outlined in this report are based on a study conducted between May and September, 1966, pursuant to a consulting agreement between the Ford Foundation and E. G. Shelley and Company, Inc." --T.p.
  Birth control -- Research; Fertility, Human -- Research; Population research; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Political science and Area II: A horse-back appraisal (Reports 002826), 1954; Bailey, Stephen K. (Stephen Kemp); Brown, Dyke; Lindsay, Franklin A. (Box 123)
  The following report grows out of a series of informal conversations held in the spring of 1954 with Dyke Brown and Frank Lindsay of the Ford Foundation ... They centered around the core issues of problem definition and resource identification.
  Political science -- Study and teaching -- United States; Political science -- Research -- United States
- Memorandum on a program of research and training in government and politics (Reports 002827), 1954; Truman, David B. (David Bicknell), 1913-2003 (Box 124)
  Political science -- Research -- United States; Political science -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- United States; Education (Graduate) -- United States
- The role of American foundations (Reports 002828), 1966; Stone, Shepard (Box 124)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- History; Nonprofit organizations -- United States
- The Foundation and the Arts - the decade of the seventies (Reports 002829), 1972 (Box 124)
  Review of Board of Trustees' 1962 guidelines setting forth the arts as a major area of concern for the Foundation.
  Arts and society -- United States; Arts -- United States -- Finance
- The Pilot Research Project in Growth Centres (Reports 002830), 1972; India. Ministry of Food, Agriculture, Community Development, and Cooperation (Box 124)
  Tile sufficient as abstract.
  Pilot research projects in growth centers (India).
  24 p. + appendices
  Pilot Research Project in Growth Centers ...
  Central places -- Research -- India; Community development -- India; Rural development -- India; India. Ministry of Food, Agriculture, Community Development, and Cooperation
- A different way to do business (Reports 002831), 1974; Staples, Eugene S. (Box 124)
  Memo to John Bresnan, dated May 28, 1974.
- Program for Asia and the Near East (Reports 002832), 1954; Ivy, James T. (Box 124)
  Asia and the Near East ...
  Charity organization -- Asia; Charity organization -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Asia; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- Suitability, possibilities and means of inter-university collaboration between Canada and Latin American countries in the field of social sciences (Reports 002833), 1965; Dion, Gérard, 1912- (Box 124)
  65 p. + appendices
  Social sciences -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Latin America; Social sciences -- Research -- Latin America; Education, Higher -- Latin America; Universities and colleges -- Latin America; College teachers -- Training of -- Latin America; Educational exchanges; Université Laval
- An investigation into special summer drama programs, Fall (Reports 002834), 1965; Candler, Peter M. (Box 124)
  55 p. + appendices
  Summer theater -- United States -- Finance; Theater -- United States -- Finance
- Equal opportunities for minority groups (Reports 002835), 1967 (Box 124)
  Includes papers from: John R. Coleman, Edward J. Meade, Malcolm Moos, Louis Winnick, and James W. Armsey.
  National Affairs/Social Development; National Affairs program/UMD; National Affairs program/G&L;Education and Research/Public Education;Education and Research/Special Programs
  Minorities -- United States -- Education; Minorities -- United States -- Employment; Minorities -- United States -- Economic conditions; Minorities -- United States -- Social conditions; Community development, Urban -- United States
- The Ford Foundation's program in school staff development, 1970-1974 (Reports 002836), Martus, Marjorie (Box 124)
  An information paper for the Education Committee of the Board of Trustees - September 1974. --T.p.
  07390811
  Policy studies, documentation, evaluation and research related to staff development for school personnel.
  Education -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Teachers -- Training of -- United States; Teacher centers -- United States; Educational assistance -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- Comments on West Pakistan's Accelerated Rice Improvement Program in cooperation with the International Rice Research Institute (Reports 002837), 1966; Chandler, Robert F. (Robert Flint), 1907-; Mueller, Kenneth E.; Golden, William G. (Box 124)
  ii, 54 p.: tables
  Rice -- Research -- Pakistan; Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Research -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia; International Rice Research Institute
- Conservation of natural resources (Reports 002838), 1963 (Box 124)
  Introduces a study to determine whether the Ford Foundation should develop a full program on conservation.
  Conservation of natural resources -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration
- The Ford Foundation-Administered Project: what and why? (Reports 002839), 1972 (Box 124)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Evaluation
- Historic and architectural preservation and restoration (Reports 002840), 1963 (Box 124)
  Architecture -- Conservation and restoration -- United States; Historic districts -- United States
- Improving educational opportunities for minorities (Reports 002841), 1968 (Box 124)
  Education and Research/Special Programs; National Affairs program/Social Development
  Minorities -- Education -- United States; African Americans -- Education -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States
- A note on the Pilot Research Project in Growth Centres second progress report (Reports 002842) (DPM 73-1), 1973 (Box 124, Box 935, Sheet DPM 73-1)
  Central places -- India; Community development -- India; Rural development -- India
- Managing educational endowments (Reports 002843), 1968 (Box 124)
  46 p. + appendices: tables
  Endowments -- United States -- Management; Portfolio management -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Finance
- Future program choices in education and research (Reports 002844), 1975 (Box 124)
  An information paper for the Education Committee of the Trustees. Prefaced by 1-page memo from Harold Howe II.
  Education -- United States; Education -- Study and teaching -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States; Literacy -- United States
- Public Affairs: Gray Areas Program (Reports 002845), 1964 (Box 124)
  Community development, Urban -- United States; Community development -- United States; City planning -- United States; Economic development projects -- United States; Urban renewal -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- Higher education for under-represented minorities FY 1971, FY 1972 and three years beyond (Reports 002846), 1970 (Box 124)
  90 p. + appendix: tables
  Minorities -- Education, Higher -- United States; African American universities and colleges -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; African Americans -- Study and teaching -- United States; Ford Foundation. Special Program in Education
- A Police Development Fund (Reports 002847), 1969; Newman, Jon O. (Jon Ormand), Jon O. (Box 125)
  22 p. + 87 p. appendices.
  Police -- United States; Police training -- United States; Law enforcement -- Study and teaching -- United States
- Medical school at Henry Ford Hospital (Reports 002848), 1963 (Box 125)
  Medical colleges -- United States -- Finance; Medicine -- Study and teaching -- United States; Henry Ford Hospital
- Middle East - Africa Program (Reports 002849), 1966 (Box 125)
  Board of Trustees;Overseas Division/Middle East and Africa
  Charity organization -- Middle East; Charity organization; Charity organization -- Africa, East; Africa, West -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa, East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa, West -- Evaluation; Philanthropy
- Overseas Development Program: notes on agricultural development (Reports 002850), 1964; Hill, F. F. (Forrest Frank) (Box 125)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Developing countries; Agricultural productivity -- Developing countries; Agricultural development projects -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- PAYE: a report to the Trustees (Reports 002851), 1971 (Box 125)
  Student loans -- United States; Education, Higher -- Finance -- United States
- Patterns of objectives and grant actions--the arts: summary and recapitulation March 1957 - September 30, 1971 (Reports 002852), 1972 (Box 125)
  Arts -- United States; Arts -- Finance -- United States; Arts and society -- United States; Arts -- Study and teaching -- United States; Minorities in art -- United States
- Program for symphony orchestras (Reports 002853), 1964 (Box 125)
  Discusses allocation of funds to consolidate the position of symphony orchestras in the United States.
  Arts -- United States -- Finance; Symphony orchestras -- United States -- Finance; Music -- United States -- Finance
- Priorities for work on the world population problem: Bellagio III (Reports 002854), 1973 (Box 125)
  Birth control -- Developing countries -- Social aspects; Birth control -- Developing countries -- Economic aspects
- Policy, program, and operational directives for the 1960s (Reports 002855), 1962 (Box 125)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Charity organization -- United States; Ford Foundation. Program
- Policy paper: population (Reports 002856), 1963 (Box 125)
  Birth control; Population assistance; Population policy; Overpopulation; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Program-directed investments (Reports 002857), 1968 (Box 125)
  Endowments -- United States -- Program-related investments; Program budgeting -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance
- A portfolio of large-scale possibilities (Reports 002858), 1971 (Box 125)
  Descriptions and supplementary materials of 10 large-scale projects for review by the Board at the time of its meeting in June 1971.
- Overseas Development Program: proposal for an International Institute of Tropical Agriculture located in Africa (Reports 002859), 1963 (Box 125)
  Agriculture -- Tropics; Agriculture -- Developing Countries; Agricultural assistance -- Developing countries; Tropical crops -- Africa; Research institutes -- Africa; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- Report of a contact making visit to Tunisia, Algeria and Morocco: January 21-29 (Reports 002860), 1976; Jolly, Richard; Cruise O'Brien, Rita (Box 125)
  This is a trip report suggested and partly funded by the Ford Foundation for two research consultants to Tunisia, Algeria and Morocco from January 21-29, 1976.[…]The main purpose of our visit was to make contact with social science research groups in the Maghreb and to explore ways in which they might establish links with research groups in the Anglophone world - particularly in Britain. The visit had been sugges,This is a trip report suggested and partly funded by the Ford Foundation for two research consultants to Tunisia
  Social sciences -- Research -- Tunisia; Social sciences -- Research -- Algeria; Social sciences -- Research -- Morocco; Research institutes -- International cooperation; Research institutes -- Africa, North
- The program of transitional support to international studies in American universities (Reports 002861), 1969 (Box 125)
  ...the Trustees approved a transitional program of support to American universities for their work in international studies. This program is intended to give assistance during the period following expiration of the major grants for international studies.
  International relations -- Study and teaching; International relations -- Research
- Program of support for land acquisition by the Nature Conservancy (Reports 002862), 1967 (Box 125)
  Natural resources -- Management -- United States; Conservation of natural resources -- United States; Ford Foundation. Resources and Environment
- Public Broadcast Laboratory of NET (Reports 002863), 1967 (Box 125)